<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[The Shackleton Expanse]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>The Shackleton Expanse</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:29:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:28:43 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[USS Nightingale]]></title><description><![CDATA[Summary
Location:: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Locations/Shackleton Expanse/The Shackleton Expanse" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Locations/Shackleton Expanse/The Shackleton Expanse" href="shackleton-expanse/locations/shackleton-expanse/the-shackleton-expanse.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Shackleton Expanse</a>
Year:: 2382<br>
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20251005-mosaic00013}.jpg" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/uss-nightingale/img-20251005-mosaic00013}.jpg" target="_self">
The NCC-60805-C: A colony support and emergency response ship.
<br>A <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="The Federation" data-href="The Federation" href="shackleton-expanse/lore/factions/the-federation.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Federation</a> Intrepid Class starship commanded by <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Robin Zhao" data-href="Robin Zhao" href="crew/robin-zhao.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Captain Robin Zhao</a>. It has a mission profile for colony support and is a first responder ship for emergencies. Federation Ship
Intrepid Class
Hope Ship
The USS Nightingale is the 3rd ship of its name. The original Nightingale was a small medical supply ship in the 2280s.
In the in the 2370s, the NCC-60805-B was a Nebula Class hospital ship commanded by Captain Nandi Jadeja. The 60805-B was sent behind enemy lines during the Cardassian insurgency, where it collected escape pods and other survivors.
The current NCC-60805-C Nightingale was commissioned in 2373 and has been serving as a colony support vessel for nearly 10 years
The Nightingale is outfitted for colony support and provides cargo transfers, medical backup, and miliary presence to new colony worlds. These colonies are the kind of places that deal with the unknowns which still appear even after years of survey and study, so the Nightingale is equipped to response flexibly to a wide variety of needs.Season 1
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 0.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 0.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-0.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 0</a>: Stardate -The crew of the USS Nightingale is recruited and prepared for duty (and friendship!)
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 1.1 - Bacchus-3.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 1.1 - Bacchus-3.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-1.1-bacchus-3.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 1.1 - Bacchus-3</a>: Stardate 56241The Nightingale arrived at Bacchus 3, where they discovered some colonists trying to activate some ancient alien ruins. The planet itself had a warp core signature at its center.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 1.2 - Bacchus-3.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 1.2 - Bacchus-3.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-1.2-bacchus-3.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 1.2 - Bacchus-3</a>: Stardate 56452The colonists of Bacchus-3 were found to have their organic material resonating with the subspace distortion waves and their mass phased into subspace. The Klingons joined the Nightingale while the away team has entered the monolith, only to trigger it’s systems.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 1.3 - Bacchus-3.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 1.3 - Bacchus-3.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-1.3-bacchus-3.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 1.3 - Bacchus-3</a>: Stardate 56452The Nightingale successfully evacuated the remaining colonists from Bacchus-3 and recovered an active buffer of other lifeforms, including what we believe are the remaining missing colonists. In the process, we deactivated the alien device causing the subspace distortion waves and rescued a Klingon ship from a warp core containment breach. The Nightingale is towing the Klingon ship back to Narendra station for repairs and to receive our next assignment.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 2 A Klingon Christmas.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 2 A Klingon Christmas.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-2-a-klingon-christmas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 2 A Klingon Christmas</a>: Stardate 56980.82<br>The Nightingale was assigned on a diplomatic mission to deliver toys of violence to children on the Klingon-Federation border. The crew was assaulted by the children, but creatively managed to deliver the gifts with minimal harm to crew or the children. The final stop involved creating a fireworks show by blowing up a shuttle. In this incident, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Valera" data-href="Valera" href="crew/valera.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lieutenant Velara</a> nearly died but was beamed off the exploding shuffle at the last moment and saved by the medical staff.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 3.1 - Orion Heist.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 3.1 - Orion Heist.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-3.1-orion-heist.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 3.1 - Orion Heist</a>: Stardate 57005A few members of the Nightingale were recruited by Admiral Stoker to find and retrieve a stolen artifact similar to the monument found on Bacchus-III. The away team took a shuttle, the USS Mackenzie, to chase after the SS Castle Rock, an Orion merchant freighter. There the Castle Rock suffered a breach when the back end crumpled from subspace distortion waves.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 3.2 - Orion Heist.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 3.2 - Orion Heist.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-3.2-orion-heist.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 3.2 - Orion Heist</a>: Stardate 57019The Crew of the USS Mackenzie boarded the Orion Castle Rock to retrieve the stolen artifact. One of the Orions was cybernetically connected with the artifact using a neural net and seemingly hypnotized by it. After a brief combat encounter, the artifact was retrieved. The Orions agreed to take a well made counterfeit copy of the artifact to sell to the Romulans.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 4 - Peas to Meet You.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 4 - Peas to Meet You.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-4-peas-to-meet-you.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 4 - Peas to Meet You</a>: Stardate 57030The crew assisted the colony of Re Alpha to transport it's bountiful produce to the struggling colony at the Yacci system. However, a popular treat called Ice Peas had an unexpected reaction to being transplanted. The crew all experienced enhanced attraction to one another until the medical and science teams were able to develop a cure.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 5.1 - Simplicity.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 5.1 - Simplicity.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-5.1-simplicity.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 5.1 - Simplicity</a>: Stardate 56748Admiral Banna Stoker boarded the Nightingale and took command of the ship. After arriving at Pasqual-I, an away team was beamed down to investigate the electromagnetic field surrounding the planet's surface. Meanwhile, another Federation vessel arrived to retrieve the admiral, by orders from Starfleet.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 5.2 - Complexity.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 5.2 - Complexity.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-5.2-complexity.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 5.2 - Complexity</a>: Stardate 56748The Nightingale's away team investigated the Tilikaal obelisk on Pasqual-1 and discovered that it was forcing an accelerated evolution for life on the planet. It was attempting to make contact with the Tilikaal but had been abandoned for thousands of years. The away team deactivated the obelisk but then were beamed off the planet by the USS Walcott. The Walcott had confronted the Nightingale to demand custody of Admiral Stoker. However, the Nightingale fled into warp speed rather than fight the Walcott.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 5.3 - Clarity.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 5.3 - Clarity.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-5.3-clarity.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 5.3 - Clarity</a>: Stardate 56748The Nightingale defended itself against a Cardassian battlecruiser, apparently with a bounty on Admiral Stoker. After the battlecruiser was defeated, Captain robin Zhao received a transmission from the USS Walcott informing them that Admiral Stoker was likely compromised by Tilikaal influence. Stoker was arrested. Her companion, Kassandra Pruitt and the alien entity possessing her, was interviewed aboard the Nightingale. Ultimately, the entity was expelled from Pruitt using a subspace anti-resonance.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 6 - Ghostbusters.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 6 - Ghostbusters.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-6-ghostbusters.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 6 - Ghostbusters</a>: Stardate 56748The Tilikaal entity was released from Kassandra Pruitt, and quickly fled into the rest of the USS Nightingale. The crews of the Nightingale and Walcott cooperated to find it. However, the entity was able to possess various other officers to get control of the Tilikaal Artifact. Along with several other Tilikaal entities, apparently gaining access to real space through the artifact, it attempted to pull the entire ship into subspace, but was thwarted by a heroic sacrifice by Lt. Grey.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 7 - Border Dispute.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 7 - Border Dispute.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-7-border-dispute.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 7 - Border Dispute</a>: Stardate 56906The Nightingale was summoned to rescue the USS Hudson, a Nova class science ship that had unexpectedly veered into Romulan space. A Romulan Warbird fired upon and disabled the Hudson. A rescue team was sent to the Hudson to investigate and provide help. There. they discovered a Romulan spy posing as a Vulcan. As the warbird wrestled wit the Hudson using a tractor beam, both sides began beaming crew off the ship. Siltec attempted to stop the spy from escaping on the Nightingale, unaware that the Romulans were beaming the spy off. Siltec has not been seen since.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 8 - Order in Court.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 8 - Order in Court.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-8-order-in-court.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 8 - Order in Court</a>: Stardate 56942While the crew of the USS Nightingale was on shore leave, Admiral Stoker stood trial, with Captain Zhao, Ensign Kader, and Lt. Relza among the witnesses. Prosecutor Loxor argued Stoker endangered Starfleet, while her lawyer Tokmoth questioned whether Stoker truly intended harm. It was found that Stoker's behavior could have been caused by ideas incepted into Stoker's mind.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 9.1 - Rescue.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 9.1 - Rescue.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-9.1-rescue.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 9.1 - Rescue</a>: Stardate 57017At a technology convention arranged to lure out Romulan agents, Siltec was forced to identify Cardassian engineers under threat to his mother, Misham Nol. Ensign Algan telepathically recognized Siltec, but a Starfleet officer was assassinated as a warning, plunging the convention into chaos. Misham was safely beamed away as Romulan agents opened fire.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 9.2 - Home Safe.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 9.2 - Home Safe.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-9.2-home-safe.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 9.2 - Home Safe</a>: Stardate 57026After Misham Nol’s evacuation, Romulan agents were arrested while their delegation beamed out. Nol lashed out at Robin Zhao and Ewasi, blaming them for Siltec’s endangerment and trying to convince her son to leave Starfleet, but Siltec refused. Later, the crew attended a promotion ceremony at Narendra Station where Algan Kader was promoted, Zephyr Grey was remembered, and Robin bid farewell to Yalis and Relza before their transfer. Season 2
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10.1 - Looking into the Abyss.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10.1 - Looking into the Abyss.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-10.1-looking-into-the-abyss.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 10.1 - Looking into the Abyss</a>: Stardate 57056, Session: 16The Nightingale pursued Romulans to Omega Draconis, where a black whole seemed to suddenly threaten life on an orbiting planet and also systems up to 100 light years away. The people living on the orbiting planet awaited their ascension, believing they were in no danger. Meanwhile, an away team entered a Tilikaal space station to find the Romulans in the control room.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10.2 - Abyss Station.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10.2 - Abyss Station.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-10.2-abyss-station.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 10.2 - Abyss Station</a>: Stardate 58191, Session: 17The away team on Abyss Station defeated the Romulans in the control room. Rala disabled the security systems, and Siltec helped sway the Romulans to defect. The crew began efforts to realign the black hole and destroy the station. Holly Jones disappeared during the mission, raising concerns.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10.3 - Displacement.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10.3 - Displacement.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-10.3-displacement.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 10.3 - Displacement</a>: Stardate 59240, Session: 18Atsad confirmed Akkara was 4,000 years out of time and infected with Tilikaal nanites. The team stabilized the black hole and sabotaged the station's singularity engines, trigginging a collapse of the entire solar system. The Ithik were beamed off their planet without full consent.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10 - Finding Faith.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10 - Finding Faith.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-10-finding-faith.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 10 - Finding Faith</a>: Stardate 59279, Session: 19Tensions with the evacuated Ithik escalated as Mayor Akkara accused Starfleet of violating their faith. Akkara's clone, avoided contact with his people, but was eventually persuaded to reach out to them, causing division amongst them. The crew eased tension by constructing a religious space for them aboard the ship, and started planning an asteroid relocation to construct a new home.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 11.1 Crystal Clear.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 11.1 Crystal Clear.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-11.1-crystal-clear.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 11.1 Crystal Clear</a>: Stardate 59317, Session: 20The Nightingale investigated a mysterious crystalline vessel near Narendra Station, discovering hundreds of non-organic sentiences within and a lodged titanium torpedo. Attempts to communicate failed as the ship began discharging energy, and Siltec and Rala pushed through heavy fire to secure the torpedo. When it was transported out, it exploded, leaving both officers critically injured and breaching the vessel’s hull.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 11.2 - Shattered Relationships.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 11.2 - Shattered Relationships.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-11.2-shattered-relationships.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 11.2 - Shattered Relationships</a>: Stardate 59317, Session: 21The torpedo on the cystal ship exploded, injuring Siltec and Rala with shrapnel. The Crystal ship split apart and in the chaos, the Zephyr industry freighters took off with stolen fragments. The crew returned to the Nightingale, tended to injuries, and debriefed. Several officers shared the blame. The Nightingale tracked down the Zephyr freighters to the Pasqual system. Kader and Terzin remained behind to help the injured alien entities, and The Nightingale prepared to follow.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 12.1 - Pasqual's Progress.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 12.1 - Pasqual's Progress.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-12.1-pasqual's-progress.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 12.1 - Pasqual's Progress</a>: Stardate 59317, Session: 22The Nightingale crew followed Zephyr Industry freighters to the Pasqual system, where the civilian corporation had lead the removal of Tilikaal artifacts from Pasqual-1. There, locals influenced by visions of an "angel" were using radio signals to call for an alien encounter. An away team discovered the Pasqual locals excavating a facility housing cybernetically enhanced humanoids similar to the Ithik.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 12.2 - Assimilation.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 12.2 - Assimilation.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-12.2-assimilation.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 12.2 - Assimilation</a>: Stardate 59317, Session: 23The crew discovered a crashed Borg vessel beneath Pasqual-1, where dormant drones and a preserved cybernetic head called the “Face of Borg” had recently reactivated. The Borg believed the Tilikaal to be their creators and sought to assimilate them to achieve perfection. Rather than destroy them, the Nightingale crew sedated the locals, disabled the vessel’s communications, and placed the Borg head into containment for study.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 12.3 - Liberation.md" data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 12.3 - Liberation.md" href="sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-12.3-liberation.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 12.3 - Liberation</a>: Stardate 59317, Session: 24The Ujul and Rala developed nanites to disinfect the Ithik-Borg on Pasqual-1. As soon as it gained independance, Rala saw in its memories that it was purposely cloned to be assimilated. When the villagers nearby woke up from the sleeping gas, Vrenta calmed calmed them down and began teaching them about the path to space travel. Holly shuttled the “Face of Borg” into hyper-secure containment aboard the Nightingale. The Nightingale is equipped with dozens of shuttles. Some notable ones are listed below!]]></description><link>uss-nightingale.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/USS Nightingale.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:22:08 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 12.3  - Liberation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ujul and Rala finished outfitting the nanite lab for de-assimilation work. Rala built a protein decompiler while Ujul went into into the buried Borg “rectangle” to collect samples. Vrenta coordinated security on the surface and Holly Jones secured the interior corridors.The Face of Borg watched with visible disappointment that the team wasn’t building it a new warp drive. It asked what would happen to it after the drones were freed. Holly answered that, if it were up to her, it would be destroyed.Ujul, carrying the protein decompiler and engineered nanites developed with Vodlin and Rala, returned to the Borg ship with a security team. They chose an Ithik-Borg drone floating in a gel vat. Ujul poured in the nanite mixture; it dissolved like ink in water, infected the drone, and the vat rejected it. The drone's body was spit onto the deck. Implants hissed and popped off one by one. The drone was in intense pain and confused. Rala used telepathy to connect and read fractured memories: the Ithik remembered only being created in a lab and then delivered to the Face of Borg for assimilation. Now it was effectively being born anew in front of the team.Outside, villagers woke up and gathered, angry that Starfleet was barring access to their holy site and fearing the Face of Borg would be taken away. Jasper tried to rally them to attack, but Vrenta countered openly, appealing to their curiosity and talking about their future among the stars and the need to be good, upstanding people if they ever wished to reach them. It was a serious Prime Directive violation, but it worked: the crowd calmed, and Vrenta spent the next few hours teaching.Meanwhile, Holly transported the Face of Borg to the USS Nightingale by shuttle and placed it in a hyper-secure containment facility.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-12.3-liberation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 12.3  - Liberation.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:20:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 12.2 - Assimilation]]></title><description><![CDATA[T’Lar, Siltec, and Vrenta ventured inside a chamber beneath a farmer's field on Pasqual-1, where they had discovered a long-buried Borg vessel. Borg drones floated in vats much like the Ithik clones. They debated attacking immediately to destroy the borg, but they opted instead to investigate further.T’Lar returned to the ship while Holly, Rala, and Ujul beamed down to reinforce the away team. Rala noted that the Borg's telepathic field had a strange sense of bliss as if dreaming. Ujul scanned the jelly the borg were in and discovered a new segment on their nanites, seemingly optimized for assimilation, unlike Ithik nanites. While exploring the inside of the borg ship, Siltec hallucinated visions of his crewmates assimilated into borg drones.Deeper inside, they found multiple dormant drones and a chamber containing the “Face of Borg”, a cybernetic head floating in a jar. Analysis revealed this Borg vessel had crashed nearly 10,000 years ago and had remained dormant until recently, when its systems came back online. The Borg were now transmitting signals, hoping to be retrieved. They spoke of their “creators,” who they believed to be the Tilikaal, and claimed that true perfection could only be achieved by assimilating them.After extended discussion, the crew decided to attempt containment and de-assimilation, rather than destruction. Vrenta deployed sleeping gas to subdue the local populace, and Ujul constructed a makeshift nanite lab on the surface with Vodlin to study and eventually neutralize the Borg assimilation. The environment was secured with an EM field to hinder Borg communications.Rala, Siltec, and Holly returned to confront the Face of Borg. Rala attempted to deceive the Borg to allow them to disconnect it from the ship so that they can assist. The Borg was cautious, but Holly intimidated the Face of Borg, telling that ultimately its life is in their hands. There's nothing it can do. The Face of Borg relented and allowed it to be disconnected from its ship.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-12.2-assimilation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 12.2 - Assimilation.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:20:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 12.1 - Pasqual's Progress]]></title><description><![CDATA[The crew began by analyzing the recovered recording of Lt. Zephyr Grey. It appeared to be an alien interrogation. Grey answered only with "Lt. Zephyr Grey, Nightingale, Federation citizen", while the voices debated whether his “aderi” could be separated from his body in order to survive wherever he was. The entities ultimately judged him too fragile for the separation, though one insisted to Grey, “Open your mind.”Meanwhile, liquid from the crystal ship displayed micro-crystals communicating via light pulses. Siltec used a probe to establish rudimentary yes/no communication.Captain Akul arrived to guard the crystal structure while the Nightingale departed. At Pasqual IV, the crew found Zephyr Industries storing monoliths removed from Pasqual-1. The company had replaced them with replicas to protect the Prime Directive. Zephyr’s parents, <a data-href="Francis and Martine" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Francis and Martine</a>, were present and agreed to return the missing crystal samples.Just as the crew prepared to leave, radio transmissions were detected from Pasqual-1, it had a voice recording that said, “We know you’re out there.” Siltec experienced a sudden, vivid hallucination of a bat-filled cave and drew his phaser before being calmed by Vrenta. Lera Tharn discreetly confiscated Siltec’s phaser. Tricorder data later showed a burst of chroniton radiation, likely interacting with the crystal shard embedded in Siltec’s eye.Lera then negotiated with Zephyr Industries clerk Eric, who admitted a civilian operation was underway, led by Banna Stoker, which had been left off the official paperwork. Tharn provided Eric with sensor logs that would help them fast-track approval.Back on Pasqual-1, the crew met Gorf, a local who claimed the monolith spoke to them and promised ascension to the stars. He introduced Jasper, a monkey-tailed man who used a crude antenna to send messages to an “ark” they were expecting. Jasper described visions of an “angel” with horns, who told them to call for help in the stars and to prepare to leave the planet. T’Lar, a Starfleet anthropologist, discovered Jasper’s script appeared written by someone else and found a map of excavation efforts near a large underground object. Siltec followed the map to a field where a hole had been dug.Inside, they found a shrine with recent food offerings and a structure labeled “Here there be angels.” Inside was a vertical shaft leading to deeper facilities. The crew climbed down a machined ladder into a Tilikaal-like structure containing control panels and familiar architecture.They finally entered a room of stasis vats filled with black-skinned, nanotech-modified humanoids similar to the Ithik, but with stark mechanical augmentations and cybernetic cables.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-12.1-pasqual's-progress.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 12.1 - Pasqual's Progress.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:54:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 11.2 - Shattered Relationships]]></title><description><![CDATA[The torpedo on the cystal ship exploded, injuring Siltec and Rala with shrapnel. The entire crystal ship was fracturing like glass. Captain Zhao had the Nightingale raise shields for safety, delaying the beam-out. In the chaos, the Zephyr Industries freighters warped away with peices of the crystal ship.Once debris cleared, the away team was transported to sickbay. Rala was concussed but generally fine. Siltec sustain a lasting injury: a crystal shard embedded in his eye. Removing it might risk losing his vision, so they kept it.In the post-mission debrief, Dr. Adsog took responsibility for leading the failed mission. Siltec blamed himself for the torpedo incident, and Rala falsely claimed to have approved Siltec’s action, hoping to preserve the relationship between Vrenta and Siltec. Terzin also admitted to firing first.The team tracked the Zephyr Industries freighters to Pasqual-1. The Nightingale assigned Kader and Terzin to remain behind and continue studying the Crystal ship. Rala, still dazed, interpreted her concussion as a spiritual experience. She immersed herself in the Ithik meditation chamber and envisioned the universe as a liquid medium like the crystal ship's fluid, with stars floating inside. She shared these insights with Kader.On the way to the Pasqual system, Vrenta tasked Siltec, Lt. Hayes, and Rala with deciphering a recording of Zephyr Grey. Rala discovered the “recording” was a telepathic memory from an anxious and exhausted mind observing Grey.Several team members worked together to decipher the recording:
Hayes traced the signal to the Seku system.
Siltec contacted his mother, sending secret hand signs to request help in locating Grey, while also receiving guidance on filtering telepathic noise.
Rala requested support in identifying the alien brainwave signatures in the signal, confirming it originated from a Tilikaal.
The contents of the recording would be looked at in the next session.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-11.2-shattered-relationships.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 11.2 - Shattered Relationships.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:53:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 11.1 Crystal Clear]]></title><description><![CDATA[The USS Nightingale returned to Narendra Station, where the crew prepared for a new mission. While onboarding new officers, Vrenta learned that Terzin Lux carried Janus’ symbiont and realized Janus had died. Preparations were interrupted when sensors detected an unidentified object approaching the station at warp speed. Its unusual readings suggested neither conventional propulsion nor cloaking, prompting General Kargan to call for its destruction. Vrenta refused, earning Kargon’s respect by instead arranging a blockade and leading the Nightingale to investigate.Upon approach, the object revealed itself as a massive crystalline vessel. Rala sensed faint telepathic activity, but communication failed, and scans showed hundreds of non-organic sentiences within its structure. Zephyr Industries claimed salvage rights and attempted to dissipate the vessel’s warp bubble, but the Nightingale convinced them to wait while the crew beamed aboard to investigate. Inside, they detected a titanium torpedo lodged within the crystalline walls and encountered a labyrinthine interior filled with both vacuum pockets and liquid-filled chambers.The crystals suddenly discharged energy against nearby ships, striking the Nightingale and Zephyr vessels. Terzin attempted to interact with the walls but was injured, while his phaser fire was mirrored back by the crystalline structures, suggesting the energy discharges might be a form of communication rather than hostility. As the away team navigated deeper, Siltec and Rala rushed toward the torpedo under heavy fire. Siltec managed to tag the device for transport, but when the Nightingale beamed it away, it detonated. The explosion left Siltec and Rala unconscious with critical injuries and blew a hole in the crystalline hull.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-11.1-crystal-clear.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 11.1 Crystal Clear.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:53:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 10 - Finding Faith]]></title><description><![CDATA[The USS Nightingale departed Chaktir carrying the evacuated Ithik and the clone known as “Ourkkara,” who had been in stasis for thousands of years. Tensions rose when Mayor Akkara accused Starfleet of kidnapping his people and Ourkkara avoided speaking with them.Vrenta and Rala tried to calm the Ithik, but Mayor Akkara resisted, viewing Starfleet’s actions as a violation of their faith. Meanwhile, Rala discovered that Ministers Vodlin and Naklep could no longer hear the harmonic pitch they once associated with the black hole, gifting them a tuning fork to aid in regaining the sound.The crew met with Captain Zhao and decided to build an Ithik religious space aboard the ship, including a nanite-filled sensory deprivation pool and sound-isolated walls. Rala proposed a feasibility study for towing an asteroid into orbit around the black hole to provide the Ithik a new home, successfully simulating its viability.Holly revealed a distorted recording of Lt. Grey, thought lost near Ithik space, but was confined to quarters after clashing with Zhao over her unauthorized use of lethal force.Conflict escalated when Mayor Akkara accused Ourkkara of being a spy and attempted to stab him. Akkara's helmet broke and it revealed he was identical to Ourkkara in every way.Rala used her asteroid simulation and the possibility of aid from the Wandering Kindred of the Song to win over key ministers, easing tensions in the cargo bay. By the session’s end, the Ithik accepted the newly built religious room aboard the Nightingale, giving the crew a path toward reconciliation and future cooperation.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-10-finding-faith.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10 - Finding Faith.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:53:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 10.3 - Displacement]]></title><description><![CDATA[With Jones still absent, Dr. Ujul focused on questioning the duplicate Akkara, who had been recovered from stasis. Atsad learned that 4,000 years had passed since Akkara’s abduction. The duplicate exhibited signs of nanite infection. He was distressed about being suddenly away from his home.Meanwhile, Rala and Vrenta stabilized the black hole’s spin. Rala confessed to stealing a component from the automaton controls to prevent misuse. Vrenta approved of the decision.Siltec and a Romulan engineer named Merdeck located the station’s power core. Siltec persuaded Merdeck to sabotage the engines and help destroy the station.To evacuate safely, Atsad and Vrenta claimed the Romulans were contaminated with nanites and needed to report to the shuttle bay. Most complied but Thal’vaek refused. Vrenta stunned him and dragged him aboard.Rala joined Siltec and Merdeck in overloading the engines. Siltec collapsed during the escape but was pulled to safety by Merdeck. The away team successfully evacuated as the station detonated.Akkara hesitated to evacuate his people. But Vrenta recommended forced evacuation. Atsad, Rala, and Siltec intervened with more empathy. Rala gifted Akkara a windchime made from latinum. Siltec gave him his hat.The Ithik were transported off their planet without warning. A monument from their observatory in the form of a telescope was also beamed aboard.Merdeck and Thal’vaek were placed in the brig.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-10.3-displacement.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10.3 - Displacement.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 10.2 - Abyss Station]]></title><description><![CDATA[Inside the control station orbiting Chaktir, Lt. Rala and Siltec approached the commander center's door Rala pretended to be sent by Romulus to offer aid. The Romulan officer Thal’vaek was in the room and Siltec recognized his voice, but stayed out of sight.Siltec opened fire when a Romulan grabbed Rala’s arm. A firefight broke out where Lt. Cmdr. Jones fired to kill and dropped one target. In the chaos, Rala accessed the station’s engineering systems and disabled the facility’s automatons. After Commander Jones stunned Thal’vaek. The rest surrendered.Vrenta wanted to try diplomacy with the Romulans, but Thal’vaek was stubborn. Rala used her telepathy to read Thal'vaek's mind and found he had been contacted by a Tal Shiar agent and ordered to recover any technology found.Siltec delivered a heartfelt speech appealing to the Romulans' loyalty to their families persuaded them to defect. Senior officer T’Vel agreed first and the others followed. Thal’vaek called them traitors.With the Romulans’ help, the team began to reorient the black hole’s jets and prepare to destroy the station before it could fall into the wrong hands. Rala and Vrenta worked at the main control consoles. Holly Jones and a Romulan went missing while allegedly seeking the engine room.Siltec continued reasoning with Thal’vaek, revealing details about his own family’s sacrifice. Thal’vaek resisted, telling Siltec that his mom was a traitor to her people. Vrenta finally ordered Siltec to stop stalling and check on Holly.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-10.2-abyss-station.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10.2 - Abyss Station.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:52:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 10.1 - Looking into the Abyss]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Nightingale was sent on a mission to the Omega Draconis system to find out what the Romulans were doing there. There, a single planet and a Neutronium space station orbiting a black hole. The black hole itself began rotating, so that it's radiation jets were aligned with the galactic plane. This threatened to utterly destroy the planet, but also throw radiation up to 100 light years away.On the planet, a landing party found a small colony of less than 1000 people called the Ithik worshiping the black hole. They seemed excited to finally have the Abyss gaze back at them, after they had observed it for thousands of years. The landing party made some attempts to explain that the black hole would obliterate them, but the Ithik remained convinced they would ascend to a high form of existence when the truth of the universe is revealed to them through the black hole.The Ithik had with them a single artifact from the Tilikaal, similar to the artifact that Banna Stoker used. Commander Vrenta used the artifact to receive a vision of the Neutronium space station. The landing party then took the artifact, beamed onto a shuttle, and went straight to the space station with only 2 hours until Chaktir would be destroyed.Siltec used the artifact as a key to enter the station. Inside, they found a small Romulan scout ship in a docking bay. Siltec was able to pick up trace heat signatures left over from when the Romulans passed by. The away team split up into two teams. Siltec and Vrenta found large security robots lined with Neutronium plugged into stations along the walls. Holly Jones and Ujul Atsad found a cloning facility and released a person who claimed to be Akkara, the "mayor" of Chaktir. They were confused about how they got there but remembered being visited by Tilikaal on Chaktir.Vrenta and Siltec were able to finally locate the station's control room, and sent directions to Cmdr. Jones and Lt. Ujul. But the Romulans were already inside.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-2/nightingale-log-10.1-looking-into-the-abyss.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 2/Nightingale Log 10.1 - Looking into the Abyss.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:52:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 9.2 - Home Safe]]></title><description><![CDATA[After the evacuation of Misham Nol, the Romulan agents responsible were quickly stunned and arrested. The Romulan delegation themselves meanwhile set up pattern enhancers and beamed out of the convention center.Misham Nol was unhappy with Starfleet handling of Siltec's situation, and blamed both Robin Zhao and Ewasi personally for the danger Siltec was in. And when she finally met Siltec at Sickbay, she attempted to convince him to leave Starfleet. She even threatened to get the Nightingale grounded and all it's crew reassigned. Siltec disarmed her with loving understanding. Starfleet needs him and it's where he belongs.Back at Narendra Station, Starfleet held a formal social event. After dinner, Algan Kader was promoting to Lieutenant JG. The promotions were given out by new leadership aboard Narendra Station: Admiral April Hebert. At this event, a small memorial was available as a final farewell to Lt. Zephyr Grey, which was visited by his parents.Robin wish Yalis and Relza farewell also, as they would be getting married and transferring to a space station.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-9.2-home-safe.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 9.2 - Home Safe.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:52:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 9.1 - Rescue]]></title><description><![CDATA[Starfleet Intelligence sources believed Siltec to be in custody of the Romulans as they attempted to learn more about the Cardassian Disruptor Spinal Lance technology. To lure his captors out, they organized a science and technology convention in the name of peace and cooperation across the Alpha and Beta quadrants. The crew of the Nightingale was brought in to display their findings from research in the Shackleton Expanse.During the convention, Siltec was disguised as a Romulan and told to identify Cardassian engineers who worked on the Spinal Lance. Though reluctant to comply, Siltec's mother, Misham Nol, was conspicuously present at the convention. Siltec's handler, Sub-Commander Thal'vaek threatened to kill her if he did not cooperate.Ensign Algan quickly identified Siltec telepathically, and notified the crew and Starfleet Intelligence. But when a Starfleet officer was killed near Misham as a warning, the innovation floor exploded into chaos. Misham was beamed out of the convention by Starfleet, just as several other Romulan agents fired on her.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-9.1-rescue.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 9.1 - Rescue.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:52:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 8 - Order in Court]]></title><description><![CDATA[Aram played Loxor the Ferengi prosecutor (non-Starfleet, most of Starfleet didn't want to touch the trial) and a guest star played Captain Ojok Tokmoth the Klingon defense lawyer Additional details learned during session:
Stoker was a Rear Admiral
The other Admiral in charge of Narendra Station was Admiral Opok Krakt (she/her), it's a joint Federation/Klingon operation
After stealing artifact, Stoker was on another ship exploring planets, encountered trouble, fled to Nightingale while being chased by USS Walcott
The artifact was stored in a special Starfleet box for safety until incident with Orions, only recently been out to be studied.
The judge was Admiral Jackson Nolan (human, he/him).Before trial, Stoker was talking to Tokmoth in a secure area/meeting room for privacy. Explains attorney/client privilege, Stoker doubts them, Tokmoth invokes Klingon honor, Stoker says not like she has a choice anyway. Tokmoth says Stoker has right to challenge them to a duel if defense not good.Opening arguments: Loxor opening argument was centered on General Orders 17 and 29 about not unnecessarily endangering Starfleet personnel or the Federation. Tokmoth opening argument is that it's our duty to explore but that we don't control what we find (invoked Prime Directive as an example) and that it's important fill in gaps with assumptions. Tokmoth says duty is to explore single question - did admiral stoker display both intent and ability to carry out crimes accused of.Review of facts, then lunch. Loxor interviewed Lt. Relza, who was against Stoker and saw no medical evidence for influence. Tokmoth talked further with Admiral Stoker, found out she considered herself a whistle-blower and that the Federation were exploiting the Tilikaal for their technology.Captain Zhao took the stand, asked questions by both sides. Loxor tried to build a case that the Tilikaal are an existential threat to the Federation. Tokmoth tried to build a case that it was Starfleet's duty to interact diplomatically with a species asking for help and that hostility and motivations can be difficult to interpret in unfamiliar cultures.Tokmoth spoke to Lt. Yalis, Yalis explained that Admiral doesn't have an ancient Tilikaal in her but does Yalis said Admiral used to be more cautious and that behavior changed after contact with artifact. Yalis also thinks Lt. Gray might have been mind-controlled into his stunt with the transporters and the ghosts.An initial interaction between Tokmoth and Algan Kader happened, can't remember if it was on the stand or asking questions.Out of courtroom, Yalis investigated artifact. Found it was broadcasting a wide/untargeted subspace signal that was probably a distress call. Also used a medical testing hologram to discover that it could have subtle effects on the brain that might affect thoughts/behavior. Yalis told Tokmoth about this. Got permission to use scanner on Admiral Stoker, Admiral Stoker's brain showed effects.Admiral Stoker took the stand, questioned by both Loxor first. If free and given a ship, she would go to a facility the Tilikaal told her about. Tried to establish a case that Stoker was serving the Tilikaal. Then Tokmoth asked questions - Admiral does not believe what she wants to do would endanger the Federation.During Admiral Stoker's questions with Tokmoth, Algan Kader noticed thoughts in the room. Admiral Krakt was angry the court martial was questioning her friend Admiral Stoker's honor. Admiral Nolan (the judge) was thinking lyrics to "Twinkle twinkle little star" to block mind-reading, on closer look Kader heard him think "I have to convict her and remove her from the picture" (referring to Admiral Stoker).Ensign Kader told Yalis he needed a disturbance so he could talk to Tokmoth. Yalis started some dyke drama with Relza and it escalated into punching, arrested, session went to recess. Kader told Tokmoth about what he heard in the judge's thoughts.When court reconvened, Tokmoth called Kader to the stand, and had him reveal what he had heard in the judge's thoughts. Admiral Krakt had Klingon security on the station arrest the judge, and a mistrial was declared.After the trial, Admiral Stoker resigned her commission, is now a civilian. Loxor and Tokmoth talked after court, acknowledged each-other as worthy adversaries, might even work together in the future. Tokmoth also talked to Ensign Kader and commended his bravery in coming forward and said helping cowards find their bravery to create a more honorable galaxy is why they became a lawyer.If Yalis is charged for the punch-up in the courtroom, Tokmoth will defend her.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-8-order-in-court.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 8 - Order in Court.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:52:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 7 - Border Dispute]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Nightingale was summoned to rescue the USS Hudson, a Nova class science ship that had unexpectedly veered into Romulan space. A Romulan Warbird fired upon and disabled the Hudson. A rescue team was sent to the Hudson to investigate and provide help. There, they discovered a Romulan spy posing as a Vulcan. As the warbird wrestled with the Hudson using a tractor beam, both sides began beaming crew off the ship. Siltec attempted to stop the spy from escaping on the Nightingale, unaware that the Romulans were beaming the spy off. Siltec has not been seen since.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-7-border-dispute.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 7 - Border Dispute.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:52:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 6 - Ghostbusters]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Tilikaal entity was released from Kassandra Pruitt, and quickly fled into the rest of the USS Nightingale. The crews of the Nightingale and Walcott cooperated to find it. However, the entity was able to possess various other officers to get control of the Tilikaal Artifact. Along with several other Tilikaal entities, apparently gaining access to real space through the artifact, it attempted to pull the entire ship into subspace, but was thwarted by a heroic sacrifice by Lt. Grey.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-6-ghostbusters.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 6 - Ghostbusters.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:52:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 5.3 - Clarity]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Nightingale defended itself against a Cardassian battlecruiser, apparently with a bounty on Admiral Stoker. After the battlecruiser was defeated, Captain robin Zhao received a transmission from the USS Walcott informing them that Admiral Stoker was likely compromised by Tilikaal influence. Stoker was arrested. Her companion, Kassandra Pruitt and the alien entity possessing her, was interviewed aboard the Nightingale. Ultimately, the entity was expelled from Pruitt using a subspace anti-resonance.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-5.3-clarity.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 5.3 - Clarity.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:52:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Siltec Nol]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: he/him
Rank: Petty Officer First Class
Species: Cardassian
Role: Security Specialist
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Siltec}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/siltec-nol/img-20250926-siltec}.png" target="_self">
Note: Formerly recruited by Starfleet Intelligence. Now just looking to do some good in the world.
<br>Siltec was born on <a data-href="Earth" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Earth</a> after <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Misham Nol" data-href="Misham Nol" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">his mother</a>, a Legate in the Obsidian Order, showed up at Jupiter Station with 1000 strips of gold pressed latinum and a stolen Cardassian shuttle. She exchanged information for certain assurances, including the protection of her unborn son. Starfleet agreed and set them up in a safehouse: Zefram Cochrane's old Montana ranch, which had since been converted into a cultural center and basic survival training post for Starfleet cadets. Siltec grew up with a love for horses and big open night skies. He would lay on the roof at night and count the stars he would visit when he got to join Starfleet. His mother did not approve, and used her influence to ensure his bid for the academy would not be accepted. But she could stop him from enlisting. She could, however, influence where his first assignment was. Siltec's heart dropped when he opened his duty papers and saw that he was headed right back to the ranch where he grew up, under the watchful eye of his mother.<br>He spent a few years running young Starfleet officers through survival training bootcamp, then watched them leave to follow his dream among the stars. When <a data-href="Starfleet Intelligence" href="shackleton-expanse/lore/factions/starfleet-intelligence.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Starfleet Intelligence</a> dropped by to offer him a deal, he leapt at the chance. Starfleet gets two things from this deal:
Siltec is a good agent.
Once his mom got him back in the nest, she wasn't nearly as forthcoming with information, so Starfleet sees this as a way to use her son's safety (and constant updates on his whereabouts and actions) as a negotiating tool. <br>Siltec only had one request: a billet aboard the <a data-href="USS Nightingale" href="uss-nightingale.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">USS Nightingale</a> and a path to adventure.Value1:: Trust, but verify
Value2:: The front line is a privilege
Value3:: I am willing to sacrifice myself for my crewmates
Value4:: Fear no evil
<br>Both <a data-href="Yalis" href="crew/yalis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Yalis</a> and Siltec have a deep love of husbandry and horses.
<br>Siltec and <a data-href="Valera" href="crew/valera.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valera</a> have a friendship forged by their shared experience of being seen as Starfleet's "bad guys" <br>Siltec reports directly to <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Artax" data-href="Artax" href="crew/artax.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Chief Petty Officer Artax</a>, <br><a data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Vrenta Ewasi" href="crew/vrenta-ewasi.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Vrenta Ewasi</a> is a Bajoran, and has a deep rooted suspicion of Siltec. This may even be well founded considering Siltec's family connection to the Obsidian Order and his relationship with Starfleet Intelligence. <br><a data-href="Misham Nol" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Misham Nol</a> is Siltec's mom. She is a former member of the Obsidian Order turned refugee. She raised Siltec on Earth. When Siltec tried to join Starfleet Academy, Misham pulled the right strings to prevent his acceptance. Then, when Siltec enlisted anyways, MIsham dug up dirt on his captain.
Table21 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFjMission1 Bacchus' Irresistible CallMission3 The Orion HeistMission4 Peas to Meet YouMission5 SimplicityMission6 SimplicityMission7 Border DisputeMission9 ConventionMission10 Abyss StationMission11 Crystal ClearMission12 Pasqual's Progress]]></description><link>crew/siltec-nol.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Siltec Nol.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:51:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 5.2 - Complexity]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Nightingale's away team investigated the Tilikaal obelisk on Pasqual-1 and discovered that it was forcing an accelerated evolution for life on the planet. It was attempting to make contact with the Tilikaal but had been abandoned for thousands of years. The away team deactivated the obelisk but then were beamed off the planet by the USS Walcott. The Walcott had confronted the Nightingale to demand custody of Admiral Stoker. However, the Nightingale fled into warp speed rather than fight the Walcott.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-5.2-complexity.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 5.2 - Complexity.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:45:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 5.1 - Simplicity]]></title><description><![CDATA[Admiral Banna Stoker boarded the Nightingale and took command of the ship. After arriving at Pasqual-I, an away team was beamed down to investigate the electromagnetic field surrounding the planet's surface. Meanwhile, another Federation vessel arrived to retrieve the admiral, by orders from Starfleet.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-5.1-simplicity.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 5.1 - Simplicity.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:45:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 4 - Peas to Meet You]]></title><description><![CDATA[The crew assisted the colony of Re Alpha to transport it's bountiful produce to the struggling colony at the Yacci system. However, a popular treat called Ice Peas had an unexpected reaction to being transplanted. The crew all experienced enhanced attraction to one another until the medical and science teams were able to develop a cure.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-4-peas-to-meet-you.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 4 - Peas to Meet You.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:45:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 3.2 - Orion Heist]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Crew of the USS Mackenzie boarded the Orion Castle Rock to retrieve the stolen artifact. One of the Orions was cybernetically connected with the artifact using a neural net and seemingly hypnotized by it. After a brief combat encounter, the artifact was retrieved. The Orions agreed to take a well made counterfeit copy of the artifact to sell to the Romulans.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-3.2-orion-heist.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 3.2 - Orion Heist.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:45:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 3.1 - Orion Heist]]></title><description><![CDATA[A few members of the Nightingale were recruited by <a data-href="Admiral Banna Stoker" href="shackleton-expanse/characters/admiral-banna-stoker.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Admiral Banna Stoker</a> to find and retrieve a stolen artifact similar to the monument found on Bacchus-III. The away team took a shuttle, the USS Mackenzie, to chase after the SS Castle Rock, an Orion merchant freighter. There the Castle Rock suffered a breach when the back end crumpled from subspace distortion waves.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-3.1-orion-heist.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 3.1 - Orion Heist.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:45:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 2 A Klingon Christmas]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Nightingale was assigned on a diplomatic mission to deliver toys of violence to children on the Klingon-Federation border. The crew was assaulted by the children, but creatively managed to deliver the gifts with minimal harm to crew or the children. The final stop involved creating a fireworks show by blowing up a shuttle. In this incident, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Valera" data-href="Valera" href="crew/valera.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lieutenant Velara</a> nearly died but was beamed off the exploding shuffle at the last moment and saved by the medical staff.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-2-a-klingon-christmas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 2 A Klingon Christmas.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:45:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 1.3 - Bacchus-3]]></title><description><![CDATA[
New One Shot! Mr. Winters, a major weapons manufacturer in Spire, is hosting a New Year's party. The Ministry would like to send a message to it's enemies. Kill Mr. Winters at his party. Don't make it look like an accident. December 30: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://startplaying.games/adventure/cm4a60m9p0036ocq65etgvz3g" target="_self">https://startplaying.games/adventure/cm4a60m9p0036ocq65etgvz3g</a>
<br>December 31: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://startplaying.games/adventure/cm4a634wn004x10v9m9go31np" target="_self">https://startplaying.games/adventure/cm4a634wn004x10v9m9go31np</a>
As always, these one shots are free for players in my ongoing campaigns! The Nightingale successfully evacuated the remaining colonists from Bacchus-3 and recovered an active buffer of other lifeforms, including what we believe are the remaining missing colonists. In the process, we deactivated the alien device causing the subspace distortion waves and rescued a Klingon ship from a warp core containment breach. The Nightingale is towing the Klingon ship back to Narendra station for repairs and to receive our next assignment.<br>Previous Session: <a data-href="Nightingale Log 1.2 - Bacchus-3" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-1.2-bacchus-3.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 1.2 - Bacchus-3</a>"
Next Session:]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-1.3-bacchus-3.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 1.3 - Bacchus-3.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:45:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 1.2 - Bacchus-3]]></title><description><![CDATA[The colonists of Bacchus-3 were found to have their organic material resonating with the subspace distortion waves and their mass phased into subspace. The Klingons joined the Nightingale while the away team has entered the monolith, only to trigger it’s systems.Previous Session: <a data-href="Nightingale Log 1.1 - Bacchus-3" href="sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-1.1-bacchus-3.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Nightingale Log 1.1 - Bacchus-3</a>"
Next Session:]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-1.2-bacchus-3.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 1.2 - Bacchus-3.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:45:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale Log 1.1 - Bacchus-3]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Nightingale arrived at Bacchus 3, where they discovered some colonists trying to activate some ancient alien ruins. The planet itself had a warp core signature at its center.]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-1.1-bacchus-3.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale Log 1.1 - Bacchus-3.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:44:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nightingale  Log 0]]></title><description><![CDATA[ Character Relationships]]></description><link>sessions/summaries/season-1/nightingale-log-0.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Sessions/Summaries/Season 1/Nightingale  Log 0.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 17:01:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jackson Hayes]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: he/him
Rank: Lieutenant JG
Species: Human
Role: Flight Controller
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-download20241104195325}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/jackson-hayes/img-20250926-download20241104195325}.png" target="_self">
Note: Ambitious and gunning for a command of his own.
Table2 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFj]]></description><link>crew/jackson-hayes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Jackson Hayes.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:51:44 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serres]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: he/him
Rank: Lt Commander
Species: Vulcan
Role: Quartermaster
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-serres-bg}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/serres/img-20250926-serres-bg}.png" target="_self">
Note: Wields bureaucracy like a bully.
<br><img alt="IMG-20250926-serres}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/serres/img-20250926-serres}.png" target="_self" style="width: 150px; max-width: 100%;">]]></description><link>crew/serres.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Serres.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:51:37 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Artax]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: he/him
Rank: Chief Petty Officer
Species: Edosian
Role: Away Team Security Chief
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Artax Avatar}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/artax/img-20250926-artax-avatar}.png" target="_self">
Note: Commands away team security, namely Siltec.
Table0 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNew]]></description><link>crew/artax.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Artax.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:51:18 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kepler Faraday]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: he/him
Rank: Lt Commander
Species: Human
Role: Operations Manager
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Kepler Faraday- bg}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/kepler-faraday/img-20250926-kepler-faraday-bg}.png" target="_self">
Note: Came up in the ranks with former Flight Controller, Lt Velara. <br>Faraday and <a data-href="Valera" href="crew/valera.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valera</a> went through the academy together and share a mentor who got them both their postings on the Nightingale when they graduated. Kepler is somewhat disappointed that When the mentor accepted a captain position on a different ship they tried to bring Valera with them and offered them a promotion and higher position on the new ship but Valera just wants to fly (and is maybe a little afraid of responsibility) so she turned it down and stayed
<br>Joined the Nightingale along with Valera and <a data-href="Captain Liu" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Captain Liu</a>
]]></description><link>crew/kepler-faraday.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Kepler Faraday.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:51:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Emergency Medical Hologram]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: -
Rank: -
Species: Hologram
Role: Ship Doctor
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-EMH - bg}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/emergency-medical-hologram/img-20250926-emh-bg}.png" target="_self">
Note: Please state the nature of your medical emergency. <br>Works most closely with <a data-href="Janus Lux" href="crew/janus-lux.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Janus Lux</a> and mentors her.
<br><img alt="IMG-20250926-EMH}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/emergency-medical-hologram/img-20250926-emh}.png" target="_self" style="width: 150px; max-width: 100%;">]]></description><link>crew/emergency-medical-hologram.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Emergency Medical Hologram.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:51:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bas Sa'mi]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: he/him
Rank: Chief Petty Officer
Species: Andorian
Role: Chief Engineer
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Bassami}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/bas-sa'mi/img-20250926-bassami}.png" target="_self">
Note: Salt of the Earth kind of Engineer, just looking to do his job.
<br><img alt="IMG-20250926-Bassami}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/bas-sa'mi/img-20250926-bassami}.png" target="_self" style="width: 150px; max-width: 100%;"><img alt="IMG-20250926-Bassami-transparent}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/bas-sa'mi/img-20250926-bassami-transparent}.png" target="_self" style="width: 150px; max-width: 100%;">]]></description><link>crew/bas-sa'mi.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Bas Sa'mi.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:49:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Robin Zhao]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: she/they
Rank: Captain
Species: Human
Role: Commanding Officer
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Pasted image 20250701082838}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/robin-zhao/img-20250926-pasted-image-20250701082838}.png" target="_self">
Note: Took up command of the Nightingale after gaining a reputation as an Emergency Response specialist.
<br>Usually found on <a data-href="The Bridge" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Bridge</a>. Previously served on the NCC-60805-B doing evacuations <br> STATBLOCK
<img alt="IMG-20250926-Pasted image 20241101155749}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/robin-zhao/img-20250926-pasted-image-20241101155749}.png" target="_self"> <br>Robin's life was saved by <a data-href="Zephyr Grey" href="crew/zephyr-grey.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Zephyr Grey</a>, and then they decided to commission and mentor him. <br>Close friends with <a data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Vrenta Ewasi" href="crew/vrenta-ewasi.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Vrenta Ewasi</a>, who Robin hand picked for this assignment. Vrenta is comfortable carrying out the harder decisions.
<br>Distrusts the <a data-href="Bas Sa'mi" href="crew/bas-sa'mi.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Bas Sa'mi</a> for being a little too aggressive.
<br><a data-href="Kepler Faraday" href="crew/kepler-faraday.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Kepler Faraday</a> is the newest of the crew, and Zhao is especially hard on them. They have big shoes to fill since they are replacing the seat of a lost crew member. <br><a data-href="Jackson Hayes" href="crew/jackson-hayes.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Jackson Hayes</a> is jealous of Grey's mentorship with the captain, and is looking to undermine that or possibly win the captain's favor.
<br><a data-href="Misham Nol" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Misham Nol</a> has leverage over Zhao, including a break in protocol that costed Cardassian lives.
Table4 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFj<br><img alt="IMG-20250926-Robin Zhao}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/robin-zhao/img-20250926-robin-zhao}.png" target="_self" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"><img alt="IMG-20250926-Robin Zhao- bg}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/robin-zhao/img-20250926-robin-zhao-bg}.png" target="_self" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;">]]></description><link>crew/robin-zhao.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Robin Zhao.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:48:25 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Algan Kader]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: he/him
Rank: Lieutenant JG
Species: Betazed
Role: Subspace Specialist
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Algan Kader- bg}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/algan-kader/img-20250926-algan-kader-bg}.png" target="_self">
Note: New and shy, but a brilliant scientist.
He's a genius who may invent something better than warp drive someday, but he's painfully shy, especially around races that speak aloud. Fresh out of the academy. He thought it would be cool to take a field posting and maybe see some spatial anomalies up close, but he's struggling to adjust to life on a starship. He's been on the Nightingale for a few weeks, and Yalis has taken him under her wing like a big sister.
<br><a data-href="Yalis" href="crew/yalis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Yalis</a> has been mentoring Kader.
<br><img alt="IMG-20250926-Algan Kader}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/algan-kader/img-20250926-algan-kader}.png" target="_self" style="width: 150px; max-width: 100%;"><img alt="IMG-20250926-Algan Kader- bg}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/algan-kader/img-20250926-algan-kader-bg}.png" target="_self" style="width: 150px; max-width: 100%;"><img alt="IMG-20250926-Algan Kader}-1.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/algan-kader/img-20250926-algan-kader}-1.png" target="_self" style="width: 150px; max-width: 100%;">]]></description><link>crew/algan-kader.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Algan Kader.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:47:54 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[T'Lar]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: she/her
Rank: Lieutenant
Species: Vulcan
Role: Anthropologist
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-T'lor - VOY Token}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/t'lar/img-20250926-t'lor-voy-token}.png" target="_self">
Note: Anthropology expert looking for the greatest mystery in her field: Who are the Tilikaal?
Table1 resultSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFj]]></description><link>crew/t'lar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/T'Lar.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:16:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gaissen]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: he/him
Rank: Lieutenant
Species: Orion
Role: Flight Controller
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Gaissen bg}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/gaissen/img-20250926-gaissen-bg}.png" target="_self">
Note: Joined Starfleet to find freedom to live his own life.
Table0 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNew]]></description><link>crew/gaissen.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Gaissen.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:15:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lara Tharn]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: she/her
Rank: Chief Petty Officer
Species: Andorian
Role: Administration
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Lara Tharn}.webp" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/lara-tharn/img-20250926-lara-tharn}.webp" target="_self">
Note: Expert in procedure and bureaucracy, and knows how to use it to her advantage.
Table1 resultSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFj]]></description><link>crew/lara-tharn.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Lara Tharn.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:14:08 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Relza, Daughter of Baylik]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: -
Rank: Lieutenant
Species: Klingon
Role: Combat Medic
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Relza}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/relza,-daughter-of-baylik/img-20250926-relza}.png" target="_self">
Note: Close friend, sparring partner, and loving spouse of Yalis. <br><a data-href="Yalis" href="crew/yalis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Yalis</a> - Close friends due to common childhood in Klingon culture. They graduated from Starfleet together and later got married
<br><img alt="IMG-20250926-Relza}-1.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/relza,-daughter-of-baylik/img-20250926-relza}-1.png" target="_self" style="width: 150px; max-width: 100%;"><img alt="IMG-20250926-Relza-transparent}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/relza,-daughter-of-baylik/img-20250926-relza-transparent}.png" target="_self" style="width: 150px; max-width: 100%;">]]></description><link>crew/relza,-daughter-of-baylik.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Relza, Daughter of Baylik.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:12:52 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Terzin Lux]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: he/him
Rank: Ensign
Species: Trill
Role: Security Attaché
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Terzin - bg}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/terzin-lux/img-20250926-terzin-bg}.png" target="_self">
Note: Lux returns to the Nightingale after the tragic death of Janus
Table2 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFj]]></description><link>crew/terzin-lux.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Terzin Lux.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:05:57 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zephyr Grey]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: he/him
Rank: Lieutenant JG
Species: Human
Role: Acquisitions Officer
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Zephyr_Grey}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/zephyr-grey/img-20250926-zephyr_grey}.png" target="_self">
Note: MISSING IN ACTION. PRESUMED DEAD
Value1:: I am more than my family's money
Value2:: Every life is worth saving
Value3:: I have a lot to prove before I can lead
Value4:: Diplomacy is the first and last resort
<br>Mentored by <a data-href="Robin Zhao" href="crew/robin-zhao.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Robin Zhao</a>. Grey rescued them from a grievous injury, which prompted them to recognize Grey's potential and commission him.
<br><a data-href="Jackson Hayes" href="crew/jackson-hayes.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Jackson Hayes</a> is jealous of Grey's mentorship with the captain, and assumes (maybe correctly) that Grey is benefitted from his family's connections with Starfleet.
<br>Shares a close friendship with <a data-href="Valera" href="crew/valera.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valera</a>, since they both grew up on the go and are more used to being in space than not.
]]></description><link>crew/zephyr-grey.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Zephyr Grey.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:52:54 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Janus Lux]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: she/her
Rank: Lieutenant JG
Species: Trill
Role: Chief Medical Officer
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Janus Lux}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/janus-lux/img-20250926-janus-lux}.png" target="_self">
Note: Working in a position far above her rank and in over her head.
Value1:: Listen to the patient; they'll tell you the diagnosis
Value2:: Sensors can't tell you everything
Value3:: One person can make a difference
Value4:: Healing comes from the heart
<br>Works closely with the <a data-href="Emergency Medical Hologram" href="crew/emergency-medical-hologram.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Emergency Medical Hologram</a> and other medical staff.
]]></description><link>crew/janus-lux.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Janus Lux.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:51:50 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Valera]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns:: she/her
Location:: Unknown
Type:: Player Character
Status:: Commissioned
NumRank:: 4
Rank:: Lieutenant
Species:: Orion
Role:: Flight Controller
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Lt_Valera}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/valera/img-20250926-lt_valera}.png" target="_self">
Note:: Speed demon most at home among the stars.
<br>Valera was born on the <a data-href="Orion" href="shackleton-expanse/locations/systems-and-planets/orion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Orion</a> starship Utuharga, and didn’t set foot on an actual planet for the first 10 years of her life. Her formative years were shaped by the independence and adaptability that life in space required, honing her instincts and skills long before formal training. She finds the gravity on most M class planets to be…weird, and has trouble sleeping without the hum of a starship. <br>At 16, during a trade negotiation mission with her family on Starbase 12, Valera seized a Federation shuttlecraft for a joyride; pushing the shuttle’s limits to evade capture, till she decided she was done and returned the shuttle. Her stunt captured the attention of <a data-href="Captain Liu" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Captain Liu</a>. Rather than meting out discipline, Liu recognized her aptitude and saw untapped potential in her. Convincing her that she could fly “further and faster” than ever before, the Liu sponsored her entry into Starfleet Academy, where Valera quickly rose to the top of her class in flight training.<br>When Liu (now Commander) was given a posting on the newly christened <a data-href="USS Nightingale" href="uss-nightingale.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">USS Nightingale</a>, Valera (along with fellow mentee <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Kepler Faraday" data-href="Kepler Faraday" href="crew/kepler-faraday.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Faraday</a>) was brought aboard to serve. When their mentor was given command of his own starship, Valera was offered a transfer and promotion, which she declined in order to stay on the Nightingale. This disappointed Faraday who told her she wasn’t living up to her potential, their friendship has been strained ever since.Cocky and sometimes brash, Valera wields humor as a shield, deflecting her insecurities with a mix of bravado and wit. Her ship and crew, however, have become her anchors, grounding her restless nature in camaraderie. She is a damn good pilot, and truly loves her ship. She’s going to be the greatest pilot Starfleet has ever seen, whatever it takes.Valera is loyal to a fault, and will step in to defend her crew. She doesn’t mind getting into trouble if it’s for “her people.”She sometimes tests the limits of her ship in ways that border on dangerous. She craves the rush of pushing technology—and herself—to the limit. This high tolerance for risk sometimes verges on carelessness, especially in tense or dangerous situations.She deflects emotional or vulnerable moments with humor, making it hard for others to see her true feelings or insecurities. Her humor can distance her from forming deeper relationships.Valera respects competence over rank.For Valera, the Nightingale isn’t just an assignment—it’s her family, a place she feels understood and needed in ways few can match.Value1:: No Home but the Stars
Value2:: Push the Limit, Find the Balance
Value3:: I am the Helm
Value4:: There’s Always a Way
<br>Both Velara and <a data-href="Zephyr Grey" href="crew/zephyr-grey.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Zephyr Grey</a> grew up on the go and share a familiarity with being in space more-so than the ground.
<br>Velara and <a data-href="Siltec Nol" href="crew/siltec-nol.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Siltec Nol</a> have a friendship forged in a common experience of being Starfleet ‘bad guys’ and occasionally getting shit for that. <br>Velara has gotten quite close with <a data-href="Jackson Hayes" href="crew/jackson-hayes.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Jackson Hayes</a> due to their shared experiences with <a data-href="Orion" href="shackleton-expanse/locations/systems-and-planets/orion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Orion</a> diplomacy. <a data-href="Jackson Hayes" href="crew/jackson-hayes.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Jackson Hayes</a> is a bit of a diplomatic brat and had seen his parents deal with Orions before. Their friendship began in Jefferies tubes.
<br><a data-href="Bas Sa'mi" href="crew/bas-sa'mi.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Bas Sa'mi</a> is uneasy with Velara on board, and suspects Velara might be using pheromones to get an advantage in her career.
<br>Velara reports directly to <a data-href="Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Vrenta Ewasi" href="crew/vrenta-ewasi.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Vrenta Ewasi</a>, and they get along. Commander Ewasi, as a Bajoran, likes a people who aren’t afraid to stand up against Starfleet. Also Piracy is cool.
Table6 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFj]]></description><link>crew/valera.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Valera.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:50:44 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Holly Jones]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: she/her
Rank: Commander
Species: Human
Role: Intelligence Officer
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Pasted image 20250701082514}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/holly-jones/img-20250926-pasted-image-20250701082514}.png" target="_self">
Note: Assigned to the Nightingale by Starfleet Intelligence to provide intel on the Expanse back to command.
Holly grew up in San Francisco, where her Mother was an Admiral. Her father was away for work most of her life, and she didn’t really know why. After she graduated from Admiral Kathryn Janeway Highschool, she joined Starfleet Academy on a Security track. During her time in the academy, she received word that her father had been killed, and she thought about quitting, but decided to continue on in his memory. After she graduated, she was assigned to the USS Firebrand, a Freedom Class ship as a Security officer. During her time on the Firebrand, she developed the skills required to be a Combat Medic by working closely with the ships doctor.About a year after joining her crew, they were patrolling near Wolf-359, when they received a hail from the USS Melbourne that the Borg had been sighted. Rushing to her aid, they watched in horror as the Borg destroyed the Melbourne. During the Battle, the Firebrand was critically damaged, and the Captain ordered the full evacuation of the crew. On her way to the escape pods, she watched a bulkhead blow infront of her, and suck out everyone into space before a force field sprang up, saving her life. Only her and the XO, Cmdr T’prel, survived. They spent 3 days floating in the debris field of the battle, not knowing if, or when, they would be rescued.After being rescued, the two were returned to Earth for debriefing, and Holly wanted to resign her commission, but Commander T’prel convinced her that that would be an insult to the memory of the crew they lost. She was promoted to a Full Lieutenant, and assigned to the USS Fresno, a California Class ship, and placed in charge of the security department. She spent the next 4 years of her life on the Fresno, before she requested some shore leave for the Anniversary of Wolf 359.Holly traveled back to Earth to meet up with Commander T’prel, who had recently been promoted to Captain. Captain T’prel informed her that she was now working with Starfleet Inelegance, and that she wanted Holly to join her, so they could work to stop another event like Wolf 359 before it even happened. What was supposed to be a quick weekend trip to remember fallen friends and crew, turned into a shift in her career. Now officially working for Intelligence, she was sent on an assignment to gather information about a new cell of the Maquis operating out of The Badlands. While investigating, she stumbled upon a small craft trying to smuggle goods off of Bajor, and was able to apprehend the pilot. Turning him over to Starfleet, she was able to ascertain where the goods were being smuggled to, and transferred the intelligence to T’prel.She then spent the next 7 years continuing to work for T’prel, becoming a prime asset for Starfleet Intelligence, building up her own network of informants. During this time, she learned from on of her informants that her Father was killed while on assignment for Starfleet Intelligence. Reeling from this information, she called her mother to subtly ask what her father did for work. Her mother replied that her father worked for Starfleet, but due to the nature of his job, was unable to verify exactly what he did. While she was doing assignments, she kept investigating her father on the side, and eventually discovered that he worked for Section 31, the secretive arm of Starfleet intelligence.One day, T’prel called her into Starfleet HQ to let her know she was going to be transferred to a starship to keep tabs on events unfolding in the Shackleton Expanse, and to listen to the orders of those above her on the ship, but remember where her loyalties lie. Holly was then promoted to Lt Commander, and given orders to travel with all due speed to Narendra Station, and board the USS Nightingale, under the command of Captain Robin Zhao.Table7 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFj]]></description><link>crew/holly-jones.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Holly Jones.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:47:06 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Yalis]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: she/her
Rank: Lieutenant
Species: Denobulan
Role: Science Officer
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Pasted image 20241031234429}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/yalis/img-20250926-pasted-image-20241031234429}.png" target="_self">
Note: Has a partially Klingon upbringing and loves discovering new species. <br>Yalis spent much of her childhood on <a data-href="Qo'noS" href="shackleton-expanse/locations/systems-and-planets/qo'nos.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Qo'noS</a>, the Klingon homeworld, where her anthropologist mother studied Klingon culture. <br>The part of her family that lived on Qo'noS returned to <a data-href="Denobula" href="shackleton-expanse/locations/systems-and-planets/denobula.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Denobula</a> for three months out of each year. Yalis was in frequent fights with Klingon children. This led to her interest in under-handed fighting tactics (size and strength don't matter if you poke someone in the eye) and also her determination to always stand up to bullies.
As a child, she read a book where humans rode horses, and became determined to ride her pet targ.
Her childhood fights and attempted targ-riding led to frequent trips to a Klingon doctor, who eventually performed a bone augmentation/strengthening procedure so she wouldn't keep breaking them. <br>She has the typical friendly and open demeanor of a Denobulan. Although she's still fairly new to <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="USS Nightingale" data-href="USS Nightingale" href="uss-nightingale.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">the ship</a> herself, Yalis will look out for new people and try to make them feel welcome.
Yalis has great memory for social interactions. Tell her the name of your dog or kids and she'll remember and ask about them by name when you talk in the future.
She does not follow the path of a Klingon warrior, but she does have a strong sense of honor when it comes to honesty and keeping her word.
She wants a traditional Denobulan family with many wives and husbands, but her sense of romance is Klingon which has kept her from finding any spouses yet.
She has the temper of a Klingon, but she keeps it under such tight wraps that usually only an empath would be able to tell when she's angry. But she survived her childhood by out-Klingoning the Klingon children, and if she perceives someone as a bully they might see a side of her that few people ever meet. <br>Yalis' favorite place on the ship is the <a data-href="Crop Sciences Lab" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Crop Sciences Lab</a>. She enjoys being around all the plants. Yalis enjoys the "seek out new life" part of the Starfleet mission - she loves first contact, she loves learning about alien cultures and getting to know them, and she loves learning about their technology and biology.
She is particularly interested in what digestive systems can tell us about the evolution, culture, and environment of a species, and is delighted if an opportunity arises to acquire a new fecal sample.
On her first posting as an Ensign, her ship encountered the Scent-of-Blueberries-and-Ammonia, a non-humanoid species with an olfactory language. Using half-completed designs from her various projects, Yalis was able to create a biochemical/scent-based Universal Translator, leading to a successful first contact.
<br>Yalis joined the crew of the <a data-href="USS Nightingale" href="uss-nightingale.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">USS Nightingale</a> 6 months ago. She liked the idea of being directly involved in helping people while also being close to the frontier where contact with new species was likely.
Value1:: I have a strong sense of honor when it comes to honesty and keeping my word.
Value2:: When I see someone in distress, I try to help them.
Value3:: Creative problem-solving can fix almost anything!
Value4:: I will always stand up to a bully.
<br>Yalis and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Siltec Nol" data-href="Siltec Nol" href="crew/siltec-nol.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Siltec</a> share a love of horses. She finally got to ride them while she was training at Starfleet Academy on Earth, and was also fascinated that any species could manage to survive with such a ridiculous digestive system. <br><a data-href="Serres" href="crew/serres.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Serres</a> - Yallis was previously reprimanded for tossing insults at them for <br><a data-href="Relza, Daughter of Baylik" href="crew/relza,-daughter-of-baylik.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Relza, Daughter of Baylik</a> and Yallisgraduated from Starfleet together and were roommates. They are frequent sparring partners.
<br><a data-href="Bas Sa'mi" href="crew/bas-sa'mi.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Bas Sa'mi</a> is a mentor to her as well as a bit of a father figure.
<br>Yalis has taken Ensign <a data-href="Algan Kader" href="crew/algan-kader.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Algan Kader</a> (a new Betazoid science ensign) under her wing like a big sister
<br>Yalis does not like <a data-href="Serres" href="crew/serres.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Serres</a>, the ship's Vulcan Chief Supply Officer, a petty little power-tripping bureaucrat. Following an incident where <a data-href="Serres" href="crew/serres.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Serres</a> restricted Ensign Kaden’s replicator access for "replicating too many writing devices" (3 in two weeks), Yalis lost her temper and called him "a massive turd obstructing the colon of scientific progress" as well as "a petaQ with a brain as smooth as his mother's forehead". <br>She narrowly avoided a reprimand for this incident, thanks to <a data-href="Bas Sa'mi" href="crew/bas-sa'mi.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Bas Sa'mi</a> intervening on her behalf with the Captain and First Officer Table15 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFj]]></description><link>crew/yalis.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Yalis.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:46:12 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ujul Adsog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: they/them
Rank: Lieutenant
Species: Klingon
Role: Ship Doctor
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Pasted image 20250701083405}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/ujul-adsog/img-20250926-pasted-image-20250701083405}.png" target="_self">
Note: On an exchange program between the Federation and the Klingon Empire.
Table8 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFj]]></description><link>crew/ujul-adsog.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Ujul Adsog.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:43:37 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Vrenta Ewasi]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: he/him
Rank: Commander
Species: Bajoran
Role: Executive Officer
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20251008-Pasted image 20250701082939}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/sekhmet/shared/crew/vrenta-ewasii/img-20251008-pasted-image-20250701082939}.png" target="_self">
Note: No nonsense commander with strong ties to Starfleet Intelligence.
<br>Second in command. Normally found in <a data-href="The Bridge" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Bridge</a>.<br> <img alt="IMG-20250926-Vrenta Ewasi- Bg}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/vrenta-ewasi/img-20250926-vrenta-ewasi-bg}.png" target="_self" style="width: 150px; max-width: 100%;"><img alt="IMG-20250926-Vrenta Ewasi}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/vrenta-ewasi/img-20250926-vrenta-ewasi}.png" target="_self" style="width: 150px; max-width: 100%;">Table11 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFj]]></description><link>crew/vrenta-ewasi.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Vrenta Ewasi.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:40:37 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rala]]></title><description><![CDATA[Info
Pronouns: she/her
Rank: Lieutenant JG
Species: Ferengi
Role: Operations Assistant
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-rala bg}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/rala/img-20250926-rala-bg}.png" target="_self">
Note: A Ferengi with a rare trait found among women that makes her telepathic.
Table7 resultsSort1Filter1PropertiesNewFjFjFjFjFj]]></description><link>crew/rala.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Rala.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 05:49:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Quentin Locke]]></title><description><![CDATA[Note
Pronouns:: he/him
Location:: <a data-href="USS Nightingale" href="uss-nightingale.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">USS Nightingale</a>
Type:: Supporting Character
Status:: Commissioned
NumRank:: 3
Rank:: Lieutenant
Species:: Human
Role:: Transporter Chief<br>
Portrait:: <img alt="IMG-20250926-Transporter Chief}.png" src="attachments/shackleton-expanse/groups/nightingale/crew/quentin-locke/img-20250926-transporter-chief}.png" target="_self">
Note:: Pushes the sliders up really well!
Value1::
Value2::
Value3::
Value4:: ]]></description><link>crew/quentin-locke.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Quentin Locke.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 05:48:10 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Meditation Chamber]]></title><description><![CDATA[Summary
Portrait::
Note:: Constructed in the lounge to give the Ithik of Chaktir a meditation and prayer space, in lieu of their black hole at Omega Draconis
]]></description><link>ship-locations/meditation-chamber.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Ship Locations/Meditation Chamber.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:36:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Marie Curie]]></title><description><![CDATA[ point 1 Continue @ [place] Description
Link: [link]
]]></description><link>ship-locations/the-marie-curie.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Ship Locations/The Marie Curie.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 03:18:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Character Relationships]]></title><description><![CDATA[Cultural DifferencesJealous of
mentorshipAccused of using pheromonesShared interest
in husbandry/horsesBoth grew up
on the go. Both more used to
being in space- Shared experiences
with Orion-Starfleet
Diplomacy
- Chance jeffery-friendshipBoth bad guys
Friendly rivalryUp through the ranks togetherGraduated
togetherreports to Bajoran likes VelaraReports to
AdmiresMentorgot reprimanded
for standing up to
he/him
Cardassian Cowboy
Security
Petty Officer
Grew up on Earth
Favourite place: holodeck
Applied to the danger ship
1 week First responder
Frontier colonies
Mass disaster
Not sure what it is - discover as we go.
secondary problems abound Security Officer Was injured, saved by Grey
Decided to fasttrack and mentor grey maybe also from a big starfleet family.
diplomatic brat she/her
Orion
Flight controller
Wants to fly!
Grew up on the go
definitely stole a starship
Lieutenant
favourite place: talks to warp core
requested to play with new nacelles
10 years - turned dow na promotion to stay bridge crew
commander / lt cmdr Andorian
Chief of Engineering
history of war with orions
Believes velara has pheromones
Luxanna but is a spy.
Has a connection to the ship, can weasel in.
Vulcan Quartermaster
Guards supplies too closely
Wields beaurocracy like a bully Field Medic he/him
Lieutentant
Human
Grew up on the go
Starfleet Academy to be a doctor
Mentored for command
Has a racing ship named after them
favourite place: observation deck
applied for the medical experience + not being recognized
1 or 2 years in she/her
Denobulan
Kronos
Heavy Klingon cultural influence.
Science - Eng
Lieutenant
crop growth lab
applied to meet new aliens
3 to 6 months Bajoran
Security background
Higher ranking
Touchy subject with cardassians
XO
]]></description><link>crew/character-relationships.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Shackleton Expanse/Groups/Nightingale/Crew/Character Relationships.canvas</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 08:02:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>